## TRISTAN LANGFORD

London SW2 2qp | 07526 938 661 | tristanlangford@hotmail.com

### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

I'm a Full Stack developer, looking for opportunities to continue challenging myself, building applications that will challenge the current technologies and benefit consumers.

Following a 5-year client-facing career in the healthcare sector, I wanted to do a job that I not only enjoyed but would make a difference. Inspired by the recent focus on technology in the healthcare sector, in early 2020 I found what I had been looking for in software development.

I have recently graduated from Makers Academy (London's leading programming bootcamp), learning best practice, tools and methodologies

### **PROJECTS**

Project/GitHub	Details	Tech
Invimcible	Group project. A top down platformer game to learn Vim commands	Express, React, Node, Redux
Acebook	Group project. Emulating the functionality of Facebook, using Ruby-on-Rails.	Ruby, Ruby-on- Rails, JavaScript
Bank Tech Test	A CLI program emulating a bank account, showcasing test driven development	JavaScript
News Summary	A single page web app, using AJAX to consume the Guardian API, using vanilla HTML, CSS, and JS.	Vanilla JS, HTML, CSS

### TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE

Languages/Frameworks – JavaScript, Node.js, React, Express, jQuery, Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS

Testing Frameworks – Jest, Mocha, Chai, Enzyme, Jasmine, RSpec

Concepts/Tools – TDD/BDD, Object-oriented design, Pair programming, Continuous Integration & Deployment

### **EXPERIENCE**

### Makers Academy

May 2020 - August 2020

#### Student

A 16-week intensive programming bootcamp. (Remote due to COVID-19 lockdown)

Primarily self-led training, encouraging students to discover/develop their own solutions, in pairs or teams.

Makers champions Agile/XP methodologies and practices, such as pair programming, TDD and OOD.

# Collaborative Procurement Partnership - (Tower 4 provider for NHS Supply Chain)

Jan 2019 - May 2020

### Category Manager - Orthopaedics

Supporting the delivery of the Future Operating Model within the NHS, through managing the relationships and contract Management with NHS Trusts in the East of England.

**Stakeholder management** with Heads of Procurement and key suppliers, to deliver cost savings for the NHS through management of a national framework (Total Orthopaedic Solutions Framework)

**Spend Analysis**, reviewing current supplier pricing offers and comparing them to the framework. Negotiating with trusts and suppliers to deliver the best saving possible while ensuring clinical quality

**Delivering change:** Quickly identified areas of weakness within the organisation and introduced processes to remove these weaknesses. Includes Supplier Relationship Management, Account Management Plan, Future Work Plan Model

SCANDIT.

OCT 2018 - Jan 2019

Sales Development Representative - UK, Nordics & Benelux

Computer vision technology company. Handle sales outreach for UK, Nordics & Benelux.

## OrthoD Group

AUG 2015 - OCT 2018

### UK Commercial Manager

Mar 2017 - Oct 2018

Hired by leading medical products business in analytical role and quickly progressed to commercial manager role with P&L accountability, maximising profit and service delivery for primary accounts, with leadership of tenders for new and existing business, working across the NHS and Department of Health.

**Influenced commercial strategy;** collaborated with CEO and CFO to improve pricing, negotiation and account retention, as well as introduction of new product range that offered substantial profit gains.

**Coached Sales Agent to meet first year target,** growing to over-performance of £98K; set ambitious but achievable objective, then provided one-to-one support, absorbing useful feedback on products and market.

✓ Created persuasive marketing tools that clarified USPs with high impact distributor incentive scheme.

Presented agile problem resolution and completed ad hoc process improvement projects:

- ✓ Enhanced client satisfaction by replacing a key product, working closely with client to define requirements.
- ✓ Resolved manufacturing back order problems; fixed root cause and improved ongoing efficiency through closer alignment of sales forecast to manufacturer production.
- ✓ Prevented account loss by heading project that offered key change in product sterilisation technique.

### **EDUCATION**

B.A. (Hons), Economics, Politics & International Relations, 2:1, Oxford Brookes University, 2015

### **HOBBIES**

Dulwich Hamlet - On a Saturday can be found standing in the "rabble" supporting Dulwich Hamlet FC

Cricket - Regularly play for one of the worst cricket teams in London (formerly officially the worst)